Register of the Gann-Duignan Papers, 1911-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
- Incremental speeches and writings, 1954-2002
  - Chronological file, 1954-2002
    - "Five Year Program for the Africa Collection," Duignan, 1961 (Box-folder 102: 5)
    - "That Fascinating Place - The Hoover Institution", circa 1961 (Box-folder 102: 6)
    - "The United States and Africa," Duignan, 1961 (Box-folder 102: 7)
    - "The Land Question of Southern Rhodesia" and "Race Relations in Southern Rhodesia, 1890-1923," Duignan, 1962 (Box-folder 102: 8)
    - "The New Establishment," Gann, 1962 (Box-folder 102: 9)
    - "Organizational Development of the National Archives of Rhodesia and Nyasaland," Gann, 1962 (Box-folder 102: 10)
    - White Settlers in Tropical Africa, 1962
      - Correspondence and reviews, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 102: 11)
      - Printed copy, chapter 4, 1962 (Box-folder 102: 12)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box-folder 102: 13-15)
    - "Archivwesen in Rhodesien und Njassaland," Gann, 1963 (Box-folder 102: 16)
    - Encyclopedia of South Africa entries, Gann, 1963 (Box-folder 102: 17)
    - "Malvern the Surgeon: An Appreciation on His Eightieth Birthday," Gann, 1963 (Box-folder 102: 18)
    - "Occasional Papers on the Politics and Economics of Contemporary Africa and the Middle East", 1963 (Box-folder 102: 19)
    - "The Southern Rhodesian Land Apportionment Act, 1930: An Essay in Trusteeship," Gann, 1963 (Box-folder 102: 20)
    - "The United States and African Slave Trade," Duignan and Clarence Clendenen, 1963 (Box-folder 163: 1)
    - History of Northern Rhodesia, reviews, Gann, 1964 (Box-folder 163: 2)
    - Huggins of Rhodesia, reviews, Gann and M. Gelfand, 1964 (Box-folder 163: 3)
    - "The Development of Southern Rhodesia's Military System, 1890-1953," Gann, 1965 (Box-folder 163: 4)
    - A History of Southern Rhodesia, Gann, 1965
      - Reviews, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 163: 5)
    - South Africa lectures, most likely by Gann, 1965-1988 (Box-folder 163: 6-7)
    - "The 'White Bastions' of Southern Africa", 1965 (Box-folder 163: 8)
    - World Publishing, "History of Africa" textbook, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 163: 9)
    - "Guerrilas and Insurgency," Gann, 1966 (Box-folder 163: 10-11)
    - Lectures by Gann, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 163: 12)
    - "Notes on a Recent Tour of Africa", 1966 (Box-folder 163: 13)
    - "African History", 1967 (Box-folder 163: 14)
    - Burden of Empire, Gann and Duignan, 1967
      - Printed copy, 1967 (Box-folder 163: 15)
      - Reviews, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 163: 16)
      - Oversize galleys, 1967 (Box 172)
    - Lewis and Clark College lectures, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 91: 1)
    - Rhodesia lectures and correspondence of Gann, 1967 (Box-folder 91: 2)
    - African political, social, and economic problems, lecture notes, circa 1968 (Box-folder 91: 3)
    - "From Ox Wagon to Armoured Car in Rhodesia," Gann, 1968 (Box-folder 91: 4)
    - "Africana Collection: A Slough of Despond," paper of Duignan delivered at the Association of Research Libraries meeting, 1969 (Box-folder 91: 5)
    - Colonialism in Africa, five volume work edited by Gann and Duignan, 1969-1975
      - Manuscripts, chapters of printed copies, correspondence, and reviews, 1969-1989 (Box-folder 91: 6-12)
    - National War College lectures, 1970 (Box-folder 91: 13)
    - Central Africa: The Former British States, Gann, 1971 (Box-folder 161: 1)
    - Guerrillas in History, Gann, 1971
      - Reviews, 1971-1988 (Box-folder 161: 2)
    - Southern Africa speeches, 1971-1976, undated (Box-folder 161: 3)
    - Africa and the World, Gann and Duignan, 1972
      - Reviews, 1973 (Box-folder 161: 4)
    - "The Military Outlook: South Africa", 1972 (Box-folder 161: 5)
    - "Rhodesia and the Prophets," Gann, 1972 (Box-folder 161: 6)
    - "Southern Africa - No Hope for Violent Liberation," Gann, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 161: 7)
    - Africa lectures and course materials, Gann, 1973, undated (Box-folder 161: 8)
      Includes lectures on Rhodesia
    - "Neo-Colonialism, Imperialism, and the 'New Class,'" Gann, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 161: 9)
    - "Subsaharan Africa" in World Communism: A Handbook, Duignan, 1973 (Box-folder 161: 10)
    - "Portugal, Africa, and the Future," Gann, 1975 (Box-folder 161: 11)
    - "Prophets Proved Wrong? The Case of Rhodesia," Gann, 1975 (Box-folder 161: 12)
    - American Historical Review articles, 1976 (Box-folder 161: 13)
    - "South Africa and the United States," Duignan, circa 1976-1977 (Box-folder 161: 14)
    - "U.S. and Iran: Our Future Relations," "Testimony on U.S. Rhodesian Relations," and lecture on the Soviet Union, circa 1976-1981 (Box-folder 161: 15)
    - Interview of Duignan, 1977 (Box-folder 161: 16)
    - Interviews in London, South Africa, and Namibia, notebook, 1977 (Box-folder 161: 17)
    - Interview notes on South Africa and Namibia work, notebook, 1977 (Box-folder 161: 18)
    - Interview notes, 1977 (Box-folder 161: 19)
    - Lectures and speeches of Gann and Duignan, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 161: 20)
    - Letter to the editor of the International Journal of African Historical Studies, 1977 (Box-folder 161: 21)
    - "Prospects for White Resistance," Gann, 1977 (Box-folder 134: 1)
    - Rulers of German Africa, Gann and Duignan, 1977
      - Correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 134: 2)
      - Printed copies of various chapters, 1977 (Box-folder 134: 3-4)
      - Reviews, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 134: 5-6)
    - "South Africa and the U.S. Arms Embargo," Gann, 1977 (Box-folder 134: 7)
    - "The White Experience in South Africa," Gann, 1977 (Box-folder 134: 8)
    - African Proconsuls, edited by Gann and Duignan, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 9-10)
    - "A Case for Détente with South Africa," Gann and Duignan, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 11-12)
    - Citation of article by Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 13)
    - "Defense of Theories Given," Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 14)
    - Disinvestment, United States, and South Africa articles, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 134: 15-16)
    - "A Fable About Money," Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 17)
    - "The Fatal Assumptions of Social Theory," Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 18)
    - "Intellectuals, Bureaucrats, and the New Sacerdotalism," Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 19)
    - "Misjudging South Africa," Gann and Duignan, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 20)
    - "Resilient SA Is not 'Decadent,'" Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 21)
    - The Rulers of British Africa, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 22-23)
    - South Africa Rockefeller papers, 1978, undated (Box-folder 134: 24)
    - "South Africa and the U.S. Arms Embargo," Gann, 1978 (Box-folder 134: 25)
    - South Africa Panel, circa 1978 (Box-folder 134: 26)
    - South Africa: War, Revolution, or Peace? Gann and Duignan, 1978
      - Poster, 1979 (Box-folder 134: 27)
      - Reviews, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 134: 28)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box-folder 134: 29-30)
    - "American Policy Toward Zimbabwe-Rhodesia: A Reappraisal," Gann, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 103: 1)
    - "Futurology: An Inexact Science," Gann, 1979 (Box-folder 103: 2)
    - "My Turn: South Africa," Gann and Duignan, 1979 (Box-folder 103: 3)
    - Oklahoma Christian College lectures, Gann, 1979, 1984 (Box-folder 103: 4)
    - Rulers of Belgian Africa, Gann and Duignan, 1979
      - Reviews, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 103: 5-6)
    - ""Rhodesia: Past, Present, Future," Gann and Duignan, 1980 (Box-folder 103: 7)
    - Speeches on the Middle East and Africa, Duignan, circa 1980 (Box-folder 103: 8)
    - The United States in the 1980s (Box-folder 103: 9-11)
    - "The Western Alliance in the Rest of the 1980s: International Affairs," Duignan, circa 1980s (Box-folder 103: 12)
    - Africa South of the Sahara, Gann and Duignan, 1981
      - Oversize galleys, 1981 (Box 173)
      - Reviews, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 103: 13)
      - Revisions, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 103: 14-15)
    - Middle East and North Africa, Gann and Duignan, 1981
      - Reviews, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 103: 16)
    - "Ministry -- New Style," Gann, circa 1981 (Box-folder 103: 17)
    - "The Price of Revolution," Gann, 1981 (Box-folder 103: 18)
    - "Racial Classification: Politics of the Future?" Gann and Alvin Rabushka, 1981 (Box-folder 103: 19)
    - Reagan, circa 1981-1982 (Box-folder 103: 20)
    - Struggle for Zimbabwe, 1981 (Box-folder 103: 21)
    - "Will South Africa Survive?", 1981-1982 (Box-folder 103: 22)
    - Why South Africa Will Survive, 1981
      - Revisions, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 103: 23)
      - Revisions (Contd.) (Box-folder 93: 1-2)
      - Reviews, 1981-1992 (Box-folder 93: 3-5)
    - "The Anti-Apartheid Movement and South Africa," Duignan, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 6)
    - "The Atlantic Alliance and East-West Relations," Gann and Duignan, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 7-8)
    - "Educational Inflation -- Increasingly Empty Minds?" Gann, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 9)
    - "Insurgency in Southern Africa," Gann, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 10)
    - "Pipelines and Peace," Gann and Duignan, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 11)
    - "Psychiatry: Helpful Servant or Cruel Master?" Gann, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 12)
    - "Report: The United States of America and the Federal Republic of Germany: Recommendations on the Treatment of Their History After World War II," review, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 13-14)
    - "South Africa Between East and West," Gann, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 15)
    - "Soviet Vulnerabilities," Gann and Michael Bernstam, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 16)
    - "Stopping the Red Juggernaut," Gann and Duignan, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 17)
    - "War and Society," Gann and Duignan, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 18)
    - "The World-Wide Threat of Soviet Communism," Duignan, circa 1982 (Box-folder 93: 19)
    - "U.S. Trade and South Africa," testimony of Gann, 1982 (Box-folder 156: 1)
    - Writings by Gann and Michael Berstam, 1982 (Box-folder 156: 2)
    - Fragment, 1983 (Box-folder 156: 3)
    - Africa Between East and West, Gann and Duignan, 1983
      - Reviews, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 156: 4)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box-folder 156: 5-7)
    - "Africa From a Globalist Perspective," Duignan, 1983 (Box-folder 156: 8)
    - Contracts, reviews, and royalties file, Duignan, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 156: 9)
    - Government and Politics in Sub-Saharan Africa Since Independence, edited by Duignan and Robert Jackson, 1983 (Box-folder 156: 10)
    - "Should the U.S. Boycott South Africa?" Gann, 1983 (Box-folder 156: 11)
    - "The USSR, South Africa, and the West," Gann, 1983 (Box-folder 156: 12)
    - "The Churches, Peace, and Communism," Gann and Alain Besançon, 1984 (Box-folder 156: 13)
    - "Khadafy's Terrorism Deserves Harsh Response," Duignan, 1984 (Box-folder 156: 14)
    - Japanese and German Empires in World War II, 1984, 1996 (Box-folder 156: 15)
    - Review of Larry Diamond essay, 1984 (Box-folder 156: 16)
    - "The Specialists in British Africa, 1880-1914," Duignan, 1984 (Box-folder 156: 17)
    - The United States and Africa, Gann and Duignan, 1984
      - Correspondence, reviews, and revisions, 1984-2000 (Box-folder 156: 18-22)
      - "The Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade", undated (Box-folder 158: 1)
    - "The USSR, the West, and South Africa," Gann, 1984 (Box-folder 158: 2)
    - "The War in Lebanon," Duignan, circa 1984 (Box-folder 158: 3)
    - "Adolf Hitler: The Complete Totalitarian," Gann, 1985 (Box-folder 158: 4)
    - "Africa From a Globalist Perspective" in African Crisis Areas and U.S. Foreign Policy, Duignan, 1985 (Box-folder 158: 5)
    - "French West German Alliance", 1985 (Box-folder 158: 6)
    - Fullerton Debate on South Africa, circa 1985-1987 (Box-folder 158: 7)
    - The Library of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, Duignan, 1985 (Box-folder 158: 8)
    - "Lord Malvern (Sir Godrey Huggins): A Reappraisal," Gann, 1985 (Box-folder 158: 9)
    - "Sanctions and Boycotts Won't Work," Duignan, 1985 (Box-folder 158: 10-11)
    - "South Africa and the Next Twelve Months," Gann and Duignan, 1985 (Box-folder 158: 12)
    - South Africa disinvestment articles, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 158: 13-14)
    - "Bishop Tutu and the South Africa Situation," Duignan, 1986 (Box-folder 158: 15)
    - Conference on United States occupations, Hoover Institution, speech most likely by Gann, 1986 (Box-folder 158: 16)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 158: 17)
    - The Hispanics in the United States: A History, Gann and Duignan, 1986
      Republished as The Spanish Speakers in the United States: A History in 1998
      - Copy-edited drafts of Spanish Speakers in the United States, undated (Box-folder 158: 18-19)
      - Reviews, 1988 (Box-folder 158: 20)
      - Typescript, 1983 (Box-folder 158: 21)
    - Op-eds in Spanish, 1986 (Box-folder 101: 1)
    - Orbis file, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 101: 2-3)
    - Politics and Government in African States, 1960-1985, Duignan and Robert H. Jackson, 1986
      - Reviews, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 101: 4-6)
        Includes review by Gann
    - "Reverse Economic Development in Africa South of the Sahara: The Future That Did Not Work," Gann and David L. Shapiro, 1986 (Box-folder 101: 7)
    - General, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 101: 8)
    - "Adventures in Thought," Advanced Abilities Center conference, Gann, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 9)
    - "Africa: What Went Wrong," speech by Duignan, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 10)
    - Articles quoting Gann and Duignan, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 11)
    - Branner Hall lecture on South Africa, Gann, circa 1987 (Box-folder 101: 12)
    - Defense of Western Europe, edited by Gann, 1987
      - Correspondence and reviews, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 101: 13)
        Includes typescript of "The U.S. and N.A.T.O."
    - "Economic Growth Is the Best Weapon," Duignan, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 14)
    - Germans in the Tropics, edited by Gann and Arthur J. Knoll
      - Correspondence and reviews, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 101: 15)
    - "Hispanic Immigrants: Legal and Illegal" and "Peter Duignan: Skilled Immigrants Aid U.S. Economy, Unskilled Illegals Hurt", 1987 (Box-folder 101: 16)
    - Hispanic writings, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 17)
    - "Historian Astray," Gann, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 18)
    - "Reverse Economic Development in Africa South of the Sahara," Gann and Shapiro, circa 1987 (Box-folder 101: 19)
    - "South Africa: What's to Be Done?" Duignan, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 20)
    - "A Time of Tyranny Will Bring on Justice," Duignan, 1987 (Box-folder 101: 21)
    - "The Berlin Conference and Humanitarian Conscience," Gann, 1988 (Box-folder 101: 22)
    - "Diseases of Africa," speech by Duignan at the Medical School, 1988 (Box-folder 101: 23)
    - "The Folly of Sanctions," Duignan, 1988 (Box-folder 101: 24)
    - Speeches, "Apartheid: Past, Present, Future," "Students for a Free South Africa," and South Africa speech at Hastings College, 1988, undated (Box-folder 117: 1)
    - Thinking About America: United States in the 1990s, 1988
      - Correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 117: 2)
    - "What Should President Bush Do in Africa?" Duignan, 1988 (Box-folder 117: 3)
    - "African Studies: A Dissident's View," Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 4-7)
      Includes correspondence and responses
    - "Ethnicity and Political Violence in Post-Colonial Africa," speech by Gann, Conference on Genocide and Political Violence at Fresno State University, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 8)
    - "Kristallnacht Reflections," Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 9)
    - Letter to the editor of The American Historical Review, Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 10)
    - "Moscow and Pretoria: A New Course?" Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 11)
    - Reviews, 1989-1999 (Box-folder 117: 12)
    - South Africa corrections, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 13)
    - " The Struggle for African Area Studies: A View From Wisconsin By Richard D. Ralston--A Response," Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 14)
    - "White Rhodesia Lecture," speech by Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 15)
    - The World and I file, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 117: 16-17)
    - "Would the Marxist-Leninist Regimes in Africa Survive the Collapse of the Soviet Regime?" Gann, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 18)
    - Zaire conference, speech by Duignan, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 19)
    - Blackwell Publishers, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 117: 20)
    - "Conflict in the Gulf," Duignan, circa 1990-1993 (Box-folder 117: 21)
    - Current Issues Seminar, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, speech by Duignan and correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 160: 1)
    - "The Future of South Africa," Duignan, 1990 (Box-folder 160: 2)
    - Lectures of Duignan, 1990 (Box-folder 160: 3)
    - United States Institute of Peace, essay on South Africa by Duignan, 1990 (Box-folder 160: 4)
    - "Wither South Africa - The Future of South Africa," speech by Duignan, 1990 (Box-folder 160: 5)
    - Hope for South Africa?
      - General, 1994, undated (Box-folder 160: 6)
      - Reviews, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 160: 7)
      - Typescripts, 1991 (Box-folder 160: 8-10)
    - "Hope for South Africa?" lectures, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 160: 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 160: 12)
    - Eastern Europe reviews, 1992 (Box-folder 160: 13)
    - "German Unification and the Left-Wing Intelligentsia: A Response." Gann, 1992 (Box-folder 160: 14)
    - Letter to the editor of The Atlantic, Gann and Duignan, 1992 (Box-folder 160: 15)
    - Mont Pèlerin Society, Vancover, Duignan, 1992 (Box-folder 160: 16)
    - NATO lectures by Gann, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 160: 17)
    - "A Realistic Policy for Sub-Sahran Africa," Gann and Thomas Henriksen, 1992 (Box-folder 160: 18)
    - The Rebirth of the West: The Americanization of the Democratic World, 1945-1958, Gann and Duignan, 1992
      - Illustrations, undated (Box-folder 160: 19)
      - Outline, undated (Box-folder 160: 20)
      - Reviews, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 160: 21)
      - Typescripts
        - General, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 106: 1-5)
        - General (Contd.), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 150: 1-3)
        - "Final", 1989 (Box-folder 150: 4-5)
        - Index, undated (Box-folder 150: 6)
        - Introduction and preface, 1989 (Box-folder 150: 7)
        - NATO, 1989 (Box-folder 150: 8)
    - "U.S. and The New Europe: Military and Geopolitical Cooperation," speech by Duignan, 1992 (Box-folder 110: 1)
    - The United States and the New Europe, Gann and Duignan, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 110: 2-8)
    - The United States and the New Europe, Gann and Duignan (Contd.) (Box-folder 176: 1-4)
    - "What Went Wrong With Marxism?" Gann and Duignan, 1992 (Box-folder 176: 5)
    - Atlantic Council Conference, correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 176: 6)
    - "Ex Africa: An Africanist's Intellectual Autobiography," Gann, 1993 (Box-folder 176: 7-8)
    - "Fall of Two Empires," Gann, 1993 (Box-folder 176: 9)
      Essay for Festschrift in honor of Milorad Drachkovitch
    - "Fall of Two Empires" (Contd.), 1993 (Box-folder 162: 1)
    - Hoover public policy papers, Duignan, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 162: 2)
    - Somalia, circa 1993 (Box-folder 162: 3)
    - "Beyond Apartheid: South Africa's Hazy Future," Gann, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 4)
    - "The Cold War in Subsaharan Africa: A Reappraisal," Duignan, circa 1994 (Box-folder 162: 5-6)
    - "The Collapse of Apartheid," Gann and Duignan, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 7)
    - Contracts, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 162: 8)
    - "Hoover Fellows: Greco-Roman Studies Have Valid Place in Modern Curriculum," Gann and Duignan, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 9)
    - "Jewish Rage," Gann, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 10)
    - "A Model for Africa," Gann, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 11)
    - "NATO: A Unique Success Story," speech by Gann, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 12)
    - Orbis file, South Africa, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 13)
      Includes typescript of "The Nelson Touch: Mandela and the Prospects for South Africa"
    - "Pitfalls That Are Awaiting South Africa," Gann, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 14)
    - Seabourn Cruise lectures of Duignan, 1994 (Box-folder 162: 15-16)
    - Fragment, 1995 (Box-folder 162: 17)
    - "The End of World War II and the Beginning of the Cold War," Gann and Duignan, 1995 (Box-folder 162: 18-19)
    - Acceptance speech of Gann upon receiving the German Order of Merit, 1995 (Box-folder 162: 19)
    - Germany lectures, Gann, 1995, undated (Box-folder 162: 20)
    - "Has Germany Evolved From Its Bloody Past?" Gann, 1995 (Box-folder 162: 21)
    - World War II essay, circa 1995 (Box-folder 162: 22)
    - "The British Military Achievement in World War II," Great War Society, lecture, 1996 (Box-folder 162: 23)
    - From Bismarck to Kohl, Gann and
      Unpublished work of Gann
      - Outline and drafts, 1996 (Box-folder 151: 1)
      - Supporting material, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 151: 2)
    - Hoover war book, decolonization chapter and supporting materials, 1996 (Box-folder 151: 3-4)
    - Immigration conference, 1996 (Box-folder 151: 5)
    - "Reflections on the Japanese and German Empires of World War II," chapter by Gann in The Japanese Wartime Empire, 1931-1945, circa 1996 (Box-folder 151: 6-8)
    - "Welcome for Immigration Conference," speech most likely by Gann, 1996 (Box-folder 151: 9)
    - "United Nations Reform?" panel discussion, Duignan, 1997 (Box-folder 151: 10)
    - Contemporary Europe and the Atlantic Alliance: A Political History, Gann and Duignan, 1998
      - Blackwell Publishers, 2002 (Box-folder 151: 11)
      - Typescripts, 1997, undated (Box-folder 151: 12-15)
      - Typescripts (Contd.) (Box-folder 167: 1-6)
      - Typescripts (Contd.) (Box-folder 153: 1-4)
    - "Let NATO Extend it's Success Story to Eastern Europe," Duignan, 1998 (Box-folder 153: 5)
    - Prop. 277 writings, Duignan, 1998 (Box-folder 153: 6)
      Includes typescripts and printed copies of "Alpert-Firestone Is Not a Good Bilingual Alternative" and "Ethnic Politics Fails Our Schoolchildren"
    - "Canada and the U.S." lecture, Duignan, circa 2000 (Box-folder 153: 7)
    - NATO: Its Past, Present, and Future, Duignan, 2000
      - Typescripts, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 153: 8-9)
    - "NATO Ten Years From Now," Duignan, 2001 (Box-folder 153: 10)
    - Noordam lectures, Duignan, 2001 (Box-folder 95: 1)
    - "Hoover's Historical Sleuths: The Curators," Duignan, 2003 (Box-folder 95: 2)
    - Making and Remaking America, Duignan and Philip Martin
      - Correspondence, 2002 (Box-folder 95: 3)
      - Typescripts, 2001 (Box-folder 95: 4-6)
  - Book reviews, 1958-1996
    Contains book reviews written by Gann and Duignan.
    - Reviews by Peter Duignan
      - 1960, 1988-1993, undated (Box-folder 95: 7-12)
    - Reviews by Lewis Gann
      - Undated (Box-folder 95: 13-14)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 95: 15)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 95: 16)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 95: 17)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 95: 18)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 95: 19)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 95: 20)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 95: 21)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 95: 22)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 95: 23)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 95: 24)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 95: 25)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 95: 26)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 95: 27)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 94: 1)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 94: 2)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 94: 3)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 94: 4)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 94: 5)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 94: 6)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 94: 7)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 94: 8)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 94: 9)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 94: 10)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 94: 11)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 94: 12)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 94: 13)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 94: 14)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 94: 15)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 94: 16)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 94: 17)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 94: 18)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 94: 19)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 94: 20)
  - Op-eds, 1980-1993
    Contains op-eds written by Gann and Duignan written on topics such as South Africa and Spanish speakers in the United States. See also chronological file.
    - General
      - 1980-1986 (Box-folder 94: 21-25)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 132: 1)
    - Hispanics, 1987 (Box-folder 132: 2)
    - Middle East, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 132: 3)
    - Reports of clippings, 1987 (Box-folder 132: 4)